<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<LanguageData>
  <!-- Breeding -->
  <RitualTargetBreeding>a shared bed</RitualTargetBreeding>
  
  <!-- Breeding Ritual Settings -->
  <BreedingRitual.OverviewHeader>Overview</BreedingRitual.OverviewHeader>
  <BreedingRitual.OverviewPara1>Any changes made to these Options will take effect immediately. It is NOT necessary to restart the game.</BreedingRitual.OverviewPara1>
  <BreedingRitual.OverviewPara2>Changes can be made at the main menu or during normal gameplay. It's slightly risky to make changes while a breeding ritual is in-progress, but you're welcome to try. If the ritual seems to get stuck, just Cancel it and try again.</BreedingRitual.OverviewPara2>
  <BreedingRitual.OverviewPara3>To use this mod:\n0. The new ritual must be part of your society's ideoligion. Either start a new game, or scroll to bottom of this page for assistance\n1. Setup a Double Bed (or any equivalent, such as Royal Bed or Double Bedroll)\n2. Assign a male and female pawn to the bed (they don't need to be in a relationship)\n3. Select the bed. You'll notice a new button: "Gather for breeding"\n4. Click this button to open the Ritual planning window.\n5. Click "Begin"</BreedingRitual.OverviewPara3>
  
  <BreedingRitual.LengthHeader>Length of the breeding ritual</BreedingRitual.LengthHeader>
  <BreedingRitual.LengthPara1>The default length is 1 in-game hour. The participants will perform Lovin' repeatedly until the allotted time runs out, and then they'll take a nap to recover. Very brief rituals may include only a single round of Lovin', whereas a long ritual provides multiple opportunities for conception.</BreedingRitual.LengthPara1>
  <BreedingRitual.LengthPara2>If you're powergaming then you should probably choose longer rituals. But if you care about pawns' quality-of-life (and/or realistic storytelling) then you should remember that a long ritual would be very strenous. If you want a compromise approach then you could choose a long duration BUT also ensure that participants consume performance-enhancing drugs before the ritual begins.</BreedingRitual.LengthPara2>
  <BreedingRitual.LengthSlider>Duration: {DURATION} hours</BreedingRitual.LengthSlider>
  
  <BreedingRitual.ArrivalHeader>Arrival method</BreedingRitual.ArrivalHeader>
  <BreedingRitual.ArrivalPara1>The ritual can't begin until both participants are in bed. The simplest option is for both of them to walk there. Alternatively, the man can bring the woman in a 'bridal carry'.</BreedingRitual.ArrivalPara1>
  <BreedingRitual.ArrivalPara2>Please note that both people must be CAPABLE of walking. A person is not eligible to participate if they're comatose, paralyzed, downed, etc. Bridal carry doesn't alter the rules; it's just a less-efficient form of locomotion which is included for flavor/roleplay reasons.</BreedingRitual.ArrivalPara2>
  <BreedingRitual.ArrivalPara3>How should the chosen couple go to bed?</BreedingRitual.ArrivalPara3>
  <BreedingRitual.ArrivalOption1>Both pawns walk</BreedingRitual.ArrivalOption1>
  <BreedingRitual.ArrivalOption1Tooltip>Both participants walk to bed.</BreedingRitual.ArrivalOption1Tooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.ArrivalOption2>Man carries woman</BreedingRitual.ArrivalOption2>
  <BreedingRitual.ArrivalOption2Tooltip>The man will retrieve the woman and carry her to bed.</BreedingRitual.ArrivalOption2Tooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.ArrivalOption3>Woman carries man</BreedingRitual.ArrivalOption3>
  <BreedingRitual.ArrivalOption3Tooltip>The woman will retrieve the man and carry him to bed.</BreedingRitual.ArrivalOption3Tooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.ArrivalPostscript>Prisoners are not officially supported. If you want to experiment then please choose an arrival method which makes sense. A prisoner is able to do Lovin' (if he's assigned to a Double Bed), but he's forbidden from leaving his cell - so he can't Bridal Carry someone unless they're standing nearby.</BreedingRitual.ArrivalPostscript>
  
  <BreedingRitual.SpectatorsHeader>Spectator Policy</BreedingRitual.SpectatorsHeader>
  <BreedingRitual.SpectatorsPara1>Spectators aren't actually needed for breeding rituals. They don't contribute to quality, so you might wish to exclude them completely. Alternatively, you can use an invite-only approach: each ritual plan will start with only two participants, but you can manually add spectators if you wish.</BreedingRitual.SpectatorsPara1>
  <BreedingRitual.SpectatorsPara2>Should spectators be included in ritual planning?</BreedingRitual.SpectatorsPara2>
  <BreedingRitual.SpectatorsOption1>Everyone is welcome</BreedingRitual.SpectatorsOption1>
  <BreedingRitual.SpectatorsOption1Tooltip>When the Ritual planning window appears, every pawn who is ELIGIBLE to spectate will be automatically assigned as a spectator. The player can selectively remove any unwanted guests. Even under this policy, some pawns are still excluded by RimWorld game rules (such as children, prisoners, downed/berserk people, etc).</BreedingRitual.SpectatorsOption1Tooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.SpectatorsOption2>By invitation only</BreedingRitual.SpectatorsOption2>
  <BreedingRitual.SpectatorsOption2Tooltip>Ritual planning begins with an empty list of spectators. The player can review the list of eligible spectators and selectively add any desired guests.</BreedingRitual.SpectatorsOption2Tooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.SpectatorsOption3>Breeding is a private affair</BreedingRitual.SpectatorsOption3>
  <BreedingRitual.SpectatorsOption3Tooltip>Spectators will NEVER be included. Only the two participants will attend.</BreedingRitual.SpectatorsOption3Tooltip>
  
  <BreedingRitual.FertilityHeader>Fertility adjustment</BreedingRitual.FertilityHeader>
  <BreedingRitual.FertilityPara1>During the breeding ritual, the couple will abide by their usual Pregnancy Approach (such as 'Avoid Pregnancy' or 'Try for Baby'). The player can use this ritual to bring together strangers, rivals, or enemies - the mod will accept any adult pawns assigned to the same bed. If the selected pawns aren't actually a couple, then their Pregnancy Approach will default to 'Normal'.</BreedingRitual.FertilityPara1>
  <BreedingRitual.FertilityPara2>I expect that players will usually select an actual couple to participate in the ritual. But the existing couple's approach might have been set to 'Avoid Pregnancy' at some point in the past.</BreedingRitual.FertilityPara2>
  <BreedingRitual.FertilityPara3>The theme of this mod is the enthusiastic celebration of babymaking. It doesn't really fit the tone if participants are hesitant about the possibility of having a child. Therefore we can temporarily force the couple to 'Try for Baby' until the ritual is complete. Alternatively, we can apply a cheat which bypasses fertility calculations and ensures conception (even for sterile pawns).</BreedingRitual.FertilityPara3>
  <BreedingRitual.FertilityPara4>Should we influence the chance of conception during a ritual?</BreedingRitual.FertilityPara4>
  <BreedingRitual.FertilityOption1>Normal</BreedingRitual.FertilityOption1>
  <BreedingRitual.FertilityOption1Tooltip>The couple will use their usual approach.</BreedingRitual.FertilityOption1Tooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.FertilityOption2>Try for Baby</BreedingRitual.FertilityOption2>
  <BreedingRitual.FertilityOption2Tooltip>A couple will always 'Try for Baby' during a breeding ritual (400% boost) but will revert to their normal approach afterwards.</BreedingRitual.FertilityOption2Tooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.FertilityOption3>Conception guaranteed (CHEAT)</BreedingRitual.FertilityOption3>
  <BreedingRitual.FertilityOption3Tooltip>A couple will always conceive during a breeding ritual, even if both of them are completely sterile. THIS IS A CHEAT!</BreedingRitual.FertilityOption3Tooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.FertilitySinglePregCheck>Single pregnancy check?</BreedingRitual.FertilitySinglePregCheck>
  <BreedingRitual.FertilitySinglePregCheckTooltip>In RimWorld, each pawn performs an independent Lovin' job. This job is usually (but not always) synchronized with their partner's job. When the job finishes, the pawn gains a happy memory and performs an RNG check for pregnancy. Thus, each round of Lovin' generates TWO simultaneous opportunities for conception. That seems like a mistake. The mod can correct it, ensuring that ritual Lovin' yields one RNG roll instead of two (the number of happy memories is unchanged).\n\nPlease keep this option in mind when viewing reports. If the mod reports that a couple performed FOUR rounds of Lovin' during a breeding ceremony, and this option is switched off, then the game probably made EIGHT conception checks.</BreedingRitual.FertilitySinglePregCheckTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.FertilityStatBasedLovin>Stats influence Lovin?</BreedingRitual.FertilityStatBasedLovin>
  <BreedingRitual.FertilityStatBasedLovinTooltip>The duration of a Lovin' action is random (anywhere from 250 ticks to 2750). This mod can reduce the randomness, making it much more stats-based. ↑Moving↑ ↑Manipulation↑ ↑Consciousness↑ and ↓Pain↓ are considered, so the player can obtain better outcomes via drugs (or bionics, magic, etc).\n\nThe revised calculation doesn't change fertility, but it allows healthier pawns to complete the task more quickly (alternatively: you might imagine that they're RECOVERING more quickly). Thus a healthy pawn will have more opportunities for conception within the same ritual timeframe.\n\nThis policy is applied ONLY during the breeding ritual. Normal Lovin' is assumed to be casual and spontaneous rather than results-focused. Uncheck this box to use the vanilla (i.e. fully random) duration for Lovin'.</BreedingRitual.FertilityStatBasedLovinTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.FertilityAvoidPregnancy>Respect 'Avoid Pregnancy'?</BreedingRitual.FertilityAvoidPregnancy>
  <BreedingRitual.FertilityAvoidPregnancyTooltip>Although this mod focuses on procreation, players might choose to perform rituals of a more 'ceremonial' nature. Perhaps certain dignitaries are obliged to participate in a fertility rite (to ensure a bountiful harvest in the coming year). If those people are currently in poor health (and/or if food is very scarce) then an actual pregnancy might be unwelcome.\n\nWhen this box is checked, the mod will respect a couple's 'Avoid Pregnancy' decision and will not override it.</BreedingRitual.FertilityAvoidPregnancyTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.FertilityPostscript>Please note that only the *participants* in the ritual are impacted. Other pawns can perform Lovin' while the ritual is ongoing, but they won't be influenced by the policy adjustment.</BreedingRitual.FertilityPostscript>
  
  <BreedingRitual.CooldownHeader>Cooldown policy</BreedingRitual.CooldownHeader>
  <BreedingRitual.CooldownPara1>For balance reasons, I recommend placing a usage restriction on this ritual. It's possible for the ritual to invoke the abilities of your ideoligion Leader, putting them on cooldown. Until the cooldown is completed, you'll be unable to perform the ritual again. You won't be able to perform the ritual AT ALL if your society doesn't yet have a Leader. Effectively, you'll need to 'spend' one usage of [Combat Command] or [Work Drive] in order to start this ritual.</BreedingRitual.CooldownPara1>
  <BreedingRitual.CooldownPara2>You can optionally switch this duty so that it impacts the Moral Guide instead. Thus, you'll be sacrificing a [Preach Health] or [Conversion] for each breeding ritual. Neither the Leader nor the Moral Guide needs to actually ATTEND the ritual; they just take a moment to give it their blessing.</BreedingRitual.CooldownPara2>
  <BreedingRitual.CooldownPara3>Why? Well, pawns normally decide when to do Lovin' and they'll do it only with people they love. Therefore RimWorld treats it as a positive experience. The Breeding ritual makes it into a duty that pawns are forced to perform. Players might pair unhappy pawns together, using a few hours of Lovin' to improve their Mood (instead of properly addressing the pawns' needs). In-universe, we could imagine the Moral Guide PERSUADING the chosen couple to participate "for the good of the tribe." The ritual would therefore be analogous to the [Reassure] ability - and it ought to be subject to the same cooldown system.</BreedingRitual.CooldownPara3>
  <BreedingRitual.CooldownPara4>If this sounds like too much hassle then you're free to ignore it. By default, the ritual can be started at any time - and it can be repeated as often as you wish.</BreedingRitual.CooldownPara4>
  <BreedingRitual.CooldownPara5>Whose special abilities should be invoked by the breeding ritual?</BreedingRitual.CooldownPara5>
  
  <BreedingRitual.CooldownOption1>Nobody (unlimited usage)</BreedingRitual.CooldownOption1>
  <BreedingRitual.CooldownOption1Tooltip>The ritual can be performed whenever the player decides to do so.</BreedingRitual.CooldownOption1Tooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.CooldownOption2>Leader</BreedingRitual.CooldownOption2>
  <BreedingRitual.CooldownOption2Tooltip>The ritual depends on the Leader's ability cooldown.</BreedingRitual.CooldownOption2Tooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.CooldownOption3>Moral Guide</BreedingRitual.CooldownOption3>
  <BreedingRitual.CooldownOption3Tooltip>The ritual depends on the Moral Guide's ability cooldown.</BreedingRitual.CooldownOption3Tooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.CooldownPostscript>Unfortunately, if you saved the game while the ritual was currently on cooldown ... then that cooldown will need to run out naturally. All *subsequent* uses of the ritual will follow your newly-selected policy.</BreedingRitual.CooldownPostscript>
  
  <BreedingRitual.PsybreedingHeader>Psybreeding</BreedingRitual.PsybreedingHeader>
  <BreedingRitual.PsybreedingPara1>Psybreeding is a variation on the normal breeding ritual. The couple must already be psychically bonded to each other, and one of them must be a psycaster. The ritual will expend all of their psyfocus as the couple attempts to achieve a perfect union of body and mind. If they succeed (i.e. they conceive a child) then the partner's latent psy abilities will be awakened.</BreedingRitual.PsybreedingPara1>
  <BreedingRitual.PsybreedingPara2>This is meant to be a major ordeal. It will require a lot of time for preparation (i.e. meditating to gather psyfocus), execution (i.e. bedroom activities), and recovery. Unlike a standard breeding (which includes many rounds of Lovin'), the couple will perform only one hours-long Lovin' action. Players should take care that no interruptions occur, lest the entire ritual be wasted.</BreedingRitual.PsybreedingPara2>
  <BreedingRitual.PsybreedingPara3>If you use the stats-based Lovin' (scroll up to find it) then young and healthy pawns will be more productive breeders - because they can complete several rounds of Lovin' per hour. This advantage doesn't apply during Psybreeding; it's inherently *slow* and it relies on a skilled psycaster (who is presumably older). You can decide which of these rituals fits your playstyle - or include both and choose whichever one best fits your couple.</BreedingRitual.PsybreedingPara3>
  <BreedingRitual.PsybreedingPara4>Spectators are allowed to attend a Psybreeding ritual, but they don't really fit the theme. If the normal ritual is a raucous communal celebration of life and hope, then this one is a private affirmation of a couple's connection to each other and the sharing of a gift. If you wish to include spectators while preserving the 'Psy' theme, there's an option for spectators to meditate instead of dancing.</BreedingRitual.PsybreedingPara4>
  <BreedingRitual.PsybreedingPara5>You can reduce the psyfocus threshold to 0 if you want, but remember that a psycaster is still required. Any psycaster who participates in this ritual will gradually expend ALL of their accumulated psyfocus - the idea is that the couple pours everything into the strengthening of their bond and the spark of a new life.</BreedingRitual.PsybreedingPara5>
  <BreedingRitual.PsybreedingPara6>Remember that accumulated psyfocus decays over time. If you set the threshold VERY high then your psycaster could fall below the limit when he stops for a snack enroute to the ritual site. It's okay to set a high threshold for thematic reasons but then reduce it slightly for gameplay reasons.</BreedingRitual.PsybreedingPara6>
  <BreedingRitual.PsybreedingPara7>If you feel that this feature is lore-unfriendly and/or overpowered, then you can simply leave it out of your ideoligion. Like the breeding ritual, psybreeding will NEVER be randomly included during Ideoligion generation. If you want to use it but feel it's slightly overpowered, then you can make it riskier by adding Neural Heat. The slider below specifies the TOTAL amount accrued over the ritual - therefore a long ritual will be safer because it allows more time for Heat to dissipate.</BreedingRitual.PsybreedingPara7>
  <BreedingRitual.PsybreedingPara8>When using neural heat, don't forget the limiter switch! The ritual will automatically be cancelled if a participant reaches their limit with their safety switch ON. Flicking the switch OFF may allow the ritual to finish - but your psycaster could suffer injuries as a result. Any gear, genes, or effects which reduce incoming Neural Heat (such as eltex robes) will make the ritual more manageable.</BreedingRitual.PsybreedingPara8>
  <BreedingRitual.PsybreedingRequirePsybond>Require psybond?</BreedingRitual.PsybreedingRequirePsybond>
  <BreedingRitual.PsybreedingRequirePsybondTooltip>This ritual is based on the concept of psychic bonding, but that Gene is quite rare in the vanilla game. If you're running mods then it may be more accessible. There's also a debug option (scroll to bottom) which will psybond a couple for testing purposes.\n\nUncheck this box if you want the ritual to be available to any couple regardless of genes or bonds.</BreedingRitual.PsybreedingRequirePsybondTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.PsybreedingBoostFertility>Psyboosted fertility?</BreedingRitual.PsybreedingBoostFertility>
  <BreedingRitual.PsybreedingBoostFertilityTooltip>This ritual calls on the couple to unite their minds, focusing intensively on the goal of conception. To reflect this, the mod applies a fertility boost equal to the sum of their Psychic Sensitivity stats. A couple with normal sensitivity would receive a 200% boost. Note that the Breeding Ritual policy (such as mandatory 'Try for Baby') applies to this ritual as well.\n\nUncheck this box to omit the special psy-boost.</BreedingRitual.PsybreedingBoostFertilityTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.PsybreedingSpectatorMeditation>Spectators meditate?</BreedingRitual.PsybreedingSpectatorMeditation>
  <BreedingRitual.PsybreedingSpectatorMeditationTooltip>Spectators can be made to meditate instead of dancing. Please remember to create a few Meditation Spots near the ritual bed (the spots don't need to be assigned; spectators will grab them opportunistically). Spectator meditation does not influence ritual quality; it's intended to be used for aesthetic or thematic purposes.</BreedingRitual.PsybreedingSpectatorMeditationTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.PsybreedingRippleVFX>Psychic VFX?</BreedingRitual.PsybreedingRippleVFX>
  <BreedingRitual.PsybreedingRippleVFXTooltip>The psybreeding ritual can display a visual "Ripple" effect, similar to the Bestowing ceremony. This is purely cosmetic; it has no impact on the participants or spectators. Uncheck this box to omit it.</BreedingRitual.PsybreedingRippleVFXTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.PsybreedingPsyfocusCost>Psyfocus needed to begin: {QUANTITY}</BreedingRitual.PsybreedingPsyfocusCost>
  <BreedingRitual.PsybreedingNeuralHeat>Neural heat: {QUANTITY}</BreedingRitual.PsybreedingNeuralHeat>
  
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingHeader>Anima Breeding</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingHeader>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingPara1>Anima Breeding splices reproduction into the anima linking ritual. You must prepare for the ritual by meditating at the anima tree. The mod has no impact on this preparation. It will require dozens of man-hours, so you're welcome to include the whole tribe. The participants don't actually need to be involved in this preparatory work, although they probably SHOULD (for narrative/flavor reasons).</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingPara1>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingPara2>You must then setup a bed near the Anima tree. A double sleeping spot is the most thematically-appropriate option, since it can be placed amidst the meadow of anima grass. If you use a constructed bed, then take care not to destroy any anima grass. Assign the bed to the two participants as usual. When the bed is selected, you'll see a button for the Anima breeding ritual alongside the usual Breeding ritual button. Remember that your society must possess the Anima breeding precept (if you don't want to start a new game, use the Debug buttons at the bottom of this page).</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingPara2>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingPara3>The ritual is intended to be very expensive (its default cost is equivalent to a Psylink level) so you should probably use it for couples who CANNOT reproduce conventionally. Infertile couples are the obvious example, but gay and lesbian couples can also conceive via anima breeding. The participants are praying to the Anima tree for a miracle; use the options below to decide which kinds of miracles are allowed (post-menopausal pregnancy? parthenogenesis? mpreg?). Please remember that pregnancy will proceed naturally. You can arrange a miraculous conception for a 90-year-old woman, but it's unlikely that she'll survive the stress of childbirth - especially in a low-tech tribal society.</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingPara3>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingPara4>Unlike most breeding rituals, spectators play a significant role here. The ritual reflects the combined hopes of the whole tribe (as embodied in the meadow of anima grass that has grown in response to their prayers). It also uses the "refund" mechanism from the Anima linking ritual - each spectator reduces the cost of the ritual, preserving some anima grass. If your tribe has been praying to the tree then you probably have Meditation Spots setup nearby; these will be used automatically during the ritual. If you're bringing in extra spectators then remember to setup a few more Spots for them. Non-tribal spectators are allowed. </BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingPara4>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingPara5>Because this is an expensive ritual, it provides an adjustable fertility boost. If you max out the slider then it's treated as Guaranteed Success - like the Cheat option above, it bypasses fertility entirely and forces conception to occur. Homosexual couples are able to conceive during anima breeding even without this cheat; a lesbian couple will have the same chance of conception as a hetero couple. The anima tree magically overcomes biological barriers, allowing the participants to mingle genes.</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingPara5>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingPara6>This options may be confusing at first glance, because the ritual is intended to be very flexible. You could use it to create children parthenogenetically (or via mystical sapphic practices) within an all-female tribe. It might help with storytelling for trans or intersex characters. It could fulfill gender equality ethics - by allowing both partners in a heterosexual couple to bear children simultaneously. You could ignore the game-mechanics and use it "narratively" instead - perhaps fiancés in an animist society cannot be married until they've lain together beneath the Anima Tree and received its blessing. Let me know if there are additional gameplay scenarios that the mod should be extended to support.</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingPara6>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingPara7>Unlike a normal Breeding ritual, the planning window for animabreeding allows you to rearrange the participants. This is important! The first assignee ("Lover") will donate genes while the second ("Childbearer") will gestate the resulting embryo. There's also an option to make the affair bi-directional - giving BOTH participants the chance to become pregnant. Please remember that Anima trees dislike artificial structures; you should probably remove your bed after the ritual has concluded (note: sleeping spots are harmless and can be left in-place permanently).</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingPara7>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingFertilityBoost>The anima breeding ritual applies a multiplicative boost to fertility calculations. If the boost is maxed out (1000%), then the mod will skip all fertility math and simply provide a guaranteed conception. Assume that the Anima performs some sort of miracle which can ignore/bypass minor inconveniences (such as vasectomy or menopause). If you'd prefer *not* to adjust the odds, you can disable the boost by setting the slider to its minimum (100%).</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingFertilityBoost>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingFertilityBoostTooltip>Multiply conception chance by: {QUANTITY}</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingFertilityBoostTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingGrassCost>By default, the ritual requires 20 anima grass (like an Anima linking ritual). Even if the cost is reduced to 0, the ritual MUST be performed close to an Anima tree (within 6 tiles).</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingGrassCost>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingGrassCostTooltip>Anima grass required to begin: {QUANTITY}</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingGrassCostTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingGrassRefund>Spectators will pray to the Anima tree during the breeding ritual. Each spectator (up to the number chosen below) will reduce the cost by 1 unit of grass. The full (non-reduced) amount of grass must be present before you can begin the ritual.</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingGrassRefund>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingGrassRefundTooltip>Spectators refund up to {QUANTITY} anima grass</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingGrassRefundTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingMalePregnancy>Allow male pregnancy?</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingMalePregnancy>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingMalePregnancyTooltip>RimWorld's backend code is quite flexible. It can support pregnancy, childbirth, and lactation for male pawns. It only really discriminates when it's CREATING pregnancies - there are several checks to ensure that male pawns don't accidentally get impregnated. The mod can disable these checks, allowing pregnancy to occur. This will happen ONLY in the context of Anima breeding, because we need miraculous intervention to overcome the obvious biological hurdles.\n\nOnce the pregnancy has begun, it will proceed normally without any further assistance from the Anima tree. Poor health can lead to an early miscarriage; the father will need typical medical care during childbirth. The father will be able to provide milk for his newborn (and he'll be auto-designated as the "Urgent" feeder).\n\nUncheck this box if you want pregnancy to remain exclusively female.</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingMalePregnancyTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingHomosexual>Allow homosexual breeding?</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingHomosexual>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingHomosexualTooltip>RimWorld allows any couple to engage in Lovin' ... but only heterosexual activities will ever generate children. The mod can override this rule, allowing homosexual couples to mingle their genes during animabreeding. Don't ask about the messy biological details - the tribe prays for a miracle, and the Anima Tree makes it happen. Children born from such unions will consider both participants to be their parents - their Relationships tab will show two mothers or two fathers.\n\nUnfortunately, RimWorld can't properly assess kinship for such children. The way that it performs Parent lookups is hetero-biased, so the daughters of a lesbian couple won't be considered "sisters" (they'll be half-sisters at best, kin at worst). There's an easy fix, but it needs a LOT of testing to guard against accidental side-effects. I'll try to include it in a future version of the mod.</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingHomosexualTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingMutual>Attempt mutual breeding?</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingMutual>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingMutualTooltip>When a Lovin' action is completed, RimWorld performs an RNG calculation based on the couple's fertility. If the check succeeds, the game attempts to create a pregnancy inside the second pawn (i.e. the woman). The mod can override this behavior during Anima breeding - the impregnation attempt becomes bidirectional. Therefore it's possible for either (or both) of the participants to become pregnant. Other options become relevant at this point - if you've disabled male pregnancy then obviously the male partner will never become pregnant.\n\nThis feature is mostly intended to allow concurrent pregnancies for lesbian couples - if you're "spending" a lot of Anima grass for a miracle, you might as well ask for TWO miracle babies instead of one.\n\nIf this box is unchecked, then *only* the second participant (the pawn who occupies the right-hand position on the Ritual planning window) can become pregnant during Anima breeding.</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingMutualTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingChildbearerGenes>Childbearer genes only?</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingChildbearerGenes>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingChildbearerGenesTooltip>The Anima ritual is intended to allow non-traditional couples to mingle their genes and create children. But some players might want even MORE freedom. If this box is checked, the mod will perform a modified RNG calculation (based on the fertility of the intended childbearer). If a pregnancy is created, the fetus will possess only one set of genes - they'll effectively be a clone of their parent.\n\nBecause RimWorld pawns can have multiple endogenes within the same category, the child may *not* be a perfect visual copy of the parent (a redhead can pass down their latent Brown Hair gene, potentially creating a dark-haired newbown).\n\nThe ritual still requires a second participant (because it's built atop a 2-person breeding ritual), but their genetics and fertility don't matter. Pretend that the Lover supports and comforts the Childbearer until the clone-ception miracle is complete.\n\nThis feature was designed to support female parthenogenesis, but it can be also be used in conjunction with male pregnancy (if that option is enabled). You could even have BOTH partners in the ritual simultaneously becoming pregnant with a clone of themselves.\n\nNote: RimWorld does not consider 'clones' to be inbred, but cloning does increase the risk of inbreeding in future generations.</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingChildbearerGenesTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingNewbornGender>Override newborn gender?</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingNewbornGender>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingNewbornGenderTooltip>A pregnancy in RimWorld is defined by a set of genes. The sex of the child is generated randomly at the moment of birth. Because this mod introduces new forms of parenthood, you might encounter absurd outcomes. For example: lesbian couples can give birth to sons. The mod can override the randomness, forcing the newborn to have a genetically-plausible sex.\n\nIf you enjoy the storytelling possibilities which arise from randomness, then you should leave this box unchecked.</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingNewbornGenderTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingBlockSterile>Prevent wasteful rituals?</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingBlockSterile>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingBlockSterileTooltip>Some players use the standard breeding ritual for entertainment, roleplay, or ceremonial purposes (and that's okay!). Since the anima breeding ritual is very expensive (in terms of anima grass), it's assumed that players will employ it only for procreation. Therefore the mod will prevent players from accidentally invoking it when the assigned couple has 0% chance to conceive.\n\nFor example: if two male pawns are assigned but the mpreg option is disabled, then the mod would block the ritual. Similarly: because RimWorld treats pregnant pawns as temporarily sterile, a pregnant woman would be unable to impregnate her non-pregnant wife during animabreeding (and so the mod would cancel the ritual). Sterile couples CAN do animabreeding (by activating one of the cheat options) - but if cheats are inactive then such couples would be excluded.\n\nUncheck this option if you want the freedom to perform "hopeless" or "wasteful" anima breeding ceremonies.</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingBlockSterileTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.PregnantSterility>Sterile during pregnancy?</BreedingRitual.PregnantSterility>
  <BreedingRitual.PregnantSterilityTooltip>By default, RimWorld inflicts temporary sterility upon any pawn for the full duration of their pregnancy. This was presumably intended to protect the pawn against becoming 'double-pregnant', but the safeguard isn't actually necessary. RimWorld automatically merges Hediffs, so a second pregnancy is harmless (it merely "accelerates" the first pregnancy by 0.1%).\n\nTemporary sterility is unimportant in the base game, but it complicates animabreeding. A pregnant woman OUGHT to be able to impregnate her wife via the magic of the Anima Tree, but RimWorld insists that the woman's fertility is 0% (and so the RNG check will fail).\n\nThe mod can solve this problem by simply *removing* the sterility side-effect of pregnancy. This has an impact on normal gameplay, but it's extremely minor (a pregnant women with a very high libido will gestate ~1% faster than a chaste woman).\n\nNote: in RimWorld, a pawn's fertility is sharply reduced while they're actively lactating. I've left this feature intact because it's an important aspect of family planning.</BreedingRitual.PregnantSterilityTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingRippleVFX>Psychic VFX?</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingRippleVFX>
  <BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingRippleVFXTooltip>The anima breeding ritual can display a visual "Pulse" effect, similar to the Anima Linking ceremony. This is purely cosmetic - it emphasizes the importance of the moment, and it distracts the player's attention from the abrupt disappearance of anima grass. Uncheck this box to omit it.</BreedingRitual.AnimabreedingRippleVFXTooltip>
  
  <BreedingRitual.MiscellaneousHeader>Miscellaneous options</BreedingRitual.MiscellaneousHeader>
  <BreedingRitual.RepetitionPenalty>Penalize repetition?</BreedingRitual.RepetitionPenalty>
  <BreedingRitual.RepetitionPenaltyTooltip>Many rituals in Rimworld impose a severe penalty to quality if they're repeated within 20 days of the previous occurrence. By default the Breeding ritual is immune to this effect, because you're expected to 'pay' with Leader ability charges. Check this box if you want to be penalized for ritual spam.</BreedingRitual.RepetitionPenaltyTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.RespectSexuality>Respect pawn sexuality?</BreedingRitual.RespectSexuality>
  <BreedingRitual.RespectSexualityTooltip>Pawns are forced to do Lovin' during a breeding ritual, regardless of their preferences. Checking this box will add a pre-check which cancels the ritual if it would contravene a pawn's sexuality. This means that Gay and Asexual pawns will be excluded from participation (although they're welcome to spectate).</BreedingRitual.RespectSexualityTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.AnnouncePregChance>Announce pregnancy chance?</BreedingRitual.AnnouncePregChance>
  <BreedingRitual.AnnouncePregChanceTooltip>At the start of a ceremony, the mod will send a message to announce the percentage likelihood of conception (per round of Lovin'). Uncheck this box to silence the mod.</BreedingRitual.AnnouncePregChanceTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.FertilityReport>Detailed fertility report?</BreedingRitual.FertilityReport>
  <BreedingRitual.FertilityReportTooltip>As with most rituals in RimWorld, you'll receive a Letter at the end of the ritual describing the various factors which influenced its quality. The mod can extend this letter, providing numerical details about fertility and performance. These numbers might harm your sense of immersion; feel free to uncheck this box if you'd rather preserve a bit of mystery.</BreedingRitual.FertilityReportTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.AllowPregnantWoman>Allow pregnant women?</BreedingRitual.AllowPregnantWoman>
  <BreedingRitual.AllowPregnantWomanTooltip>By default, a pregnant woman is ineligible to participate (though she's welcome to spectate). This is intended to protect the player from accidentally wasting resources on a redundant ceremony. However, some mods might allows for 'super pregnancy' - or players might want to do the ritual for storytelling reasons.\n\nCheck this box if you think a pregnant woman should be treated as a normal breeding candidate.</BreedingRitual.AllowPregnantWomanTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.OrganizerGetsMemory>Boss gets memory?</BreedingRitual.OrganizerGetsMemory>
  <BreedingRitual.OrganizerGetsMemoryTooltip>Participants and spectators will gain a memory about the ritual, providing a small boost or penalty to Mood. If an Ideoligion specialist (Leader or Moral Guide) 'spent' their special abilities in order to start the ritual, then we can grant them this memory as well. Obviously this is redundant if they participate or spectate; the checkbox option will grant them a memory even if they DO NOT attend the ritual.\n\nUncheck this box if memories should be given ONLY to attendees.</BreedingRitual.OrganizerGetsMemoryTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.PlayInstruments>Play instruments?</BreedingRitual.PlayInstruments>
  <BreedingRitual.PlayInstrumentsTooltip>By default, half of the spectators will attempt to play nearby instruments while the other half will dance. This has no impact on ritual quality; it's just done for thematic reasons. Uncheck this box if you want ALL of the spectators to dance.</BreedingRitual.PlayInstrumentsTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.IdeoSFX>Play ideoligion music?</BreedingRitual.IdeoSFX>
  <BreedingRitual.IdeoSFXTooltip>Rituals can generate background music which matches your Ideoligion. This is disabled by default for the breeding ritual, because it's assumed that your pawns will play instruments. Check this box to activate the standard music.</BreedingRitual.IdeoSFXTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.IdeoVFX>Show ideoligion VFX?</BreedingRitual.IdeoVFX>
  <BreedingRitual.IdeoVFXTooltip>Rituals usually generate a visual overlay at the ritual site, and a few props are drawn nearby which represent the theme of your ideoligion (such as totem poles). These tend to work well for a grandiose ceremony, but they may appear silly if you're organizing a breeding ritual within a small bedroom. Uncheck this box to disable the visual effects.</BreedingRitual.IdeoVFXTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.FarewellHuddle>Farewell huddle?</BreedingRitual.FarewellHuddle>
  <BreedingRitual.FarewellHuddleTooltip>When the participants have finished Lovin', spectators will approach to offer congratulations and prayers. This has no effect on ritual quality; it's just done for thematic reasons. Uncheck this box if you'd prefer to see them to dance and play music until the end of the ritual.</BreedingRitual.FarewellHuddleTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.GradualDispersal>Gradual dispersal?</BreedingRitual.GradualDispersal>
  <BreedingRitual.GradualDispersalTooltip>The ritual concludes with spectators approaching to offer their blessings, while the couple cuddles together. This is supposed to be a peaceful conclusion, so it looks bad if everyone sprints away simultaneously. By default, spectators will sneak away individually as the ceremony winds down - leaving the couple alone to nap.\n\nUncheck this box if you want to maintain a strict attendance policy.</BreedingRitual.GradualDispersalTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.BedUsageOverride>Bed usage tolerance?</BreedingRitual.BedUsageOverride>
  <BreedingRitual.BedUsageOverrideTooltip>RimWorld enforces many rules regarding propriety of bed usage. These rules tend to block mingling across social lines (colonists - slaves - guests - prisoners). The mod can override all of these, ensuring that a pawn can always USE the bed to which he's been ASSIGNED.\n\nYou may need to use tricks and mods to assign one of your people to a prisoner's bed, but with this option you'll be able to make the assigned couple perform a Breeding Ritual. Uncheck if you'd rather use standard RimWorld rules.\n\nIf you uncheck this option then trying to force Lovin' across social categories will probably generate errors.</BreedingRitual.BedUsageOverrideTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.AllowGuestBreeding>Allow guest breeding?</BreedingRitual.AllowGuestBreeding>
  <BreedingRitual.AllowGuestBreedingTooltip>When a group of Hospitality guests visits your colony, they're treated as 'belonging' to a Lord (an entity which directs the visit). In order for a Guest to participate in Breeding we must emancipate the Guest from their Lord; the mod does this automatically. We return them to their Lord when the breeding ritual is over, but the process isn't perfect. The Guest will wander around idly for a while before resuming normal Guest behavior.\n\nIf their group departed during the breeding, the Guest will leave independently (similar to an injured guest who needed to convalesce in your hospital). If you try to breed the ENTIRE visiting party then the Lord gets culled and the faction will send you an angry letter (their delegation suddenly vanished - and they hold YOU responsible).\n\nUncheck this box to make Guests ineligible for breeding.</BreedingRitual.AllowGuestBreedingTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.AttachableOutcomes>Bonus outcomes?</BreedingRitual.AttachableOutcomes>
  <BreedingRitual.AttachableOutcomesTooltip>When you generate an Ideoligion, it's possible to include a bonus effect for many Rituals. High-quality rituals can attract new colonists to join, recharge psyfocus for participants, etc. Some players might feel that breeding is a sufficient reward ... but if you'd like more of an incentive then you should check this box.\n\nNote that previously-generated Rituals will NOT gain any bonus effects; you'll need to generate a new Ideoligion if you want to customize them. You can also use debug tools to add+remove the breeding ritual precept; each one will get a random bonus (and you can re-roll until you're satisfied).</BreedingRitual.AttachableOutcomesTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.SuppressIdeoErrors>Hide ideoligion errors?</BreedingRitual.SuppressIdeoErrors>
  <BreedingRitual.SuppressIdeoErrorsTooltip>Ideoligions may have precepts which disallow the casual sharing of beds (because the ideoligion scorns premarital lovin', or because it absolutely forbids physical intimacy). Mods like Breeding Ritual and Manual Lovin' can (optionally) overcome these restrictions, but doing so will often generate an error message (because RimWorld assumes that the bed shenanigans happened due to a bug or mistake).\n\nIf you wish to do a lot of casual breeding (especially with guests or prisoners) then these error messages may become annoying. Check this box to suppress them.</BreedingRitual.SuppressIdeoErrorsTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.BreedingIsMarriage>Breeding is marriage?</BreedingRitual.BreedingIsMarriage>
  <BreedingRitual.BreedingIsMarriageTooltip>If the breeding couple is already engaged to be married, then we can optionally treat the breeding ritual as a crude marriage. The participants won't gain the usual happy memories (because they've missed out on the public affirmation and celebration of their love) but you won't need to worry about a wedding randomly occurring at an inconvenient moment. It's an unromantic but practical solution, which might be appropriate for a very poor colony (and/or an ascetic ideoligion). Alternatively, you could treat it as an elopement (with the couple CHOOSING to skip out on the expected festivities).\n\nIf you think fiances should be allowed to engage in pre-marital breeding (and still have normal wedding ceremonies afterwards), then leave this box unchecked.\n\nNote: this feature applies ONLY to fiances; the mod will NOT spontaneously marry people who participate in a "casual" breeding session.</BreedingRitual.BreedingIsMarriageTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.EvaluateBeautyOutdoors>Evaluate outdoor beauty?</BreedingRitual.EvaluateBeautyOutdoors>
  <BreedingRitual.EvaluateBeautyOutdoorsTooltip>Room Impressiveness is one of the contributing factors to the quality of a Breeding Ritual. It's included so that players have an incentive to setup pleasant bedrooms.\n\nLow-tech tribal societies might prefer to perform breeding ceremonies outdoors. Anima breeding can only occur outdoors. Therefore the mod can look at the breeding bed and assess the nearby Beauty value. A 10x multiplier is used, so a Beauty rating of 12 would be equivalent to Room Impressiveness of 120 ("extremely impressive"). Tidy up the area, plant a few flowers, and you'll receive a modest boost to the quality of your breeding ceremonies.</BreedingRitual.EvaluateBeautyOutdoorsTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.EvaluateBeautyIndoors>Evaluate indoor beauty?</BreedingRitual.EvaluateBeautyIndoors>
  <BreedingRitual.EvaluateBeautyIndoorsTooltip>Please review the previous entry.\n\nWe can also substitute Beauty for Room Impressiveness when evaluating INDOOR rituals. This is usually disadvantageous for the player, because it's much easier to boost Impressiveness. This feature is included mainly for flexibility and experimentation. Uncheck this box to use the normal Room Impressiveness calculation.</BreedingRitual.EvaluateBeautyIndoorsTooltip>
  <BreedingRitual.SurroundingBeauty>nearby beauty</BreedingRitual.SurroundingBeauty>
  <BreedingRitual.RoomImpressiveness>room impressiveness</BreedingRitual.RoomImpressiveness>
  
  <BreedingRitual.DebugHeader>Debug tools</BreedingRitual.DebugHeader>
  <BreedingRitual.DebugPara1>The recommended usage of this mod is:\n1.Start a new game\n2.Create a new ideoligion\n3.Add the breeding ritual to your ideoligion\n4.Playtest for a while (you can try the ritual immediately - just setup a Double Sleeping Spot on the grass)\n5.Decide whether you want to keep the mod or remove it</BreedingRitual.DebugPara1>
  <BreedingRitual.DebugPara2>If you'd like to continue using the mod, but you don't want to start over and lose progress, try the button below. It will attempt to identify your colony's dominant ideoligion, and then inject a breeding ritual into that ideoligion's precepts. Obviously you must load a savegame before doing this. I encourage you to make a backup of your savegame file before clicking the button, just in case something goes wrong.</BreedingRitual.DebugPara2>
  <BreedingRitual.DebugPara3>Note that your ability to USE this ritual depends on the rules of your ideoligion. Total prohibition of physical love means pawns can't share beds, so you'll never be able to start the ritual. In that case, you'd need to generate a new colony.</BreedingRitual.DebugPara3>
  <BreedingRitual.DebugPara4>There's another button below to remove the ritual. This could be used temporarily for GUI tidiness ("I don't want to see that Breeding gizmo appear whenever I click a bed! I'll re-add the ritual when I'm ready to perform a ceremony!"). But the expected usage is to PERMANENTLY remove the ritual from a savegame prior to uninstalling the mod. Doing so should ensure that you don't receive any red error messages re: missing RitualDefs.</BreedingRitual.DebugPara4>
  
  <BreedingRitual.DebugButton1>Add Breeding Ritual</BreedingRitual.DebugButton1>
  <BreedingRitual.DebugButton2>Add Psybreeding Ritual</BreedingRitual.DebugButton2>
  <BreedingRitual.DebugButton3>Remove Breeding Ritual</BreedingRitual.DebugButton3>
  <BreedingRitual.DebugButton4>Remove Psybreeding Ritual</BreedingRitual.DebugButton4>
  <BreedingRitual.DebugButton5>Bond this couple</BreedingRitual.DebugButton5>
  <BreedingRitual.DebugButton6>Add Animabreeding Ritual</BreedingRitual.DebugButton6>
  <BreedingRitual.DebugButton7>Remove Animabreeding Ritual</BreedingRitual.DebugButton7>
  
</LanguageData>